salutations at the
time of making this video it is 7 a.m
when i wake up every single morning not
buying my own accord so much as that my
dog iger decides around this time
that i have slept long enough
let me know if your schedule is also
dictated by animals
[Music]
today i wanted to reflect a bit on what
my home has taught me
these are my personal experiences and
they have guided me
in many ways
one thing i quickly learned once i moved
is that your space complements your
happiness but
can't necessarily sustain it my cottage
taught me
that i am responsible for my own
satisfaction in life
we often fill our minds with what-ifs
and dreams of living somewhere beautiful
that
melts away our troubles but from my
experience this
isn't an effective long-term remedy the
excitement of living here temporarily
distracted me from my troubles but
eventually i had to face them if i
didn't the void in my spirit would
poison each new environment i found
forcing me to keep moving and trying new
things in order to
outrun personal growth
as a side note i know some people were
wondering how and where i
shower and the answer is kind of strange
in the summertime i have a little
outdoor extension
that works really well but in the winter
when it's cold and i can't have heated
water
i go to a tiny house that is actually
connected to the property
and right behind my cottage it is
currently empty
and so i'm able to use the facilities
do
something else i learned is that some
inconveniences are
a matter of perspective it can be easy
to see a flushing toilet
a stable internet connection and various
other resources
as necessary for comfortable living
this may be true for some people and i
absolutely respect their preference
but as for me i have found much freedom
in altering my mindset away from
wants and towards needs i don't have a
shower inside my cottage i use a compost
toilet
and i have to take a short walk every
day in order to get a stable
connection to the internet i do my work
on my computer and then
increasingly disconnect for the rest of
the day
don't get me wrong i love technology and
it is a wonderful resource
at home i use it intentionally listening
to audiobooks watching pre-downloaded
videos and documentaries
i try to use technology in a way that
benefits me and makes me feel more
energized
instead of inadequate and mentally dull
which i find i feel sometimes after
staring at my phone for a long time
this is only my experience and of course
i would love to hear
yours
[Music]
so
another inconvenience i've learned to
deal with is looking forward to
traveling out of town in order to buy
bulk groceries
food in town is a bit limited and
expensive
so i try to stock up when i can i've had
friends who visit who have found these
inconveniences very troublesome
since they're used to having these
things available all the time
i've come to see these limitations as a
small price to pay for all the other
resources available to me
such as endless hiking trails
substantial land to use for gardening
and honestly the beauty of the mountains
and forests and grasslands
that being said rural living is
definitely not for everyone
so
[Music]
do
so
one of the biggest lessons i've received
from my cottage is that
boredom is not only underrated it is a
tool that has endless potential
for creativity and innovation when you
take something out of your life you
often naturally fill it with something
new
the less time you spend on your phone or
maybe doing other more mindless tasks
the more you realize how important it is
to have hobbies or interests that are
your own
be it learning new things like creating
art going on adventures
writing planning for example i would
have never started my youtube channel or
my etsy shop
if i hadn't found myself without
anything in particular to do
in my free time so i decided that i
wanted to start working on making my
passions into something that would help
me sustain myself
in the future
[Music]
lastly my cottage has also reminded me
to be
ever more grateful i live in an
environment of extremes with burning hot
summers and icy winters
i'm so grateful for warmth windows a
furnace and winter
i also recognize all the little
blessings that have brought me to where
i
am and cherish each in my heart in a
future video i wish to speak more on my
unusual
childhood and wonderful family
my
[Music]
thank you all for your lovely comments
and support
i truly wish i could reach out to each
one of you and answer you personally
while that is not possible for me know
that i read
all that you send me and that i deeply
appreciate it
sending my love have a lovely day or
night